Ryan McCarthy

Telephone: (613) 617-4214

Email: RyanMcCarthy613@gmail.com

Background

Received certification in Business Data Analytics from Cornell University with a focus on Excel and its vast array of tools for data analysis from compiling and organizing financial data to prescriptive analytics. Ten years of government experience, six with an Emergency Management group. Currently undergoing a Coding Bootcamp with Carleton University for the purpose of becoming a full-stack web developer.

Experience

Operations & Hardware Administrator

Ford - Ottawa Engineering Centre

October 2019 - Present

- Manage the shipping & receiving department for 800+ employees.
- Manage the tracking and distribution of hardware to employees for the development purposes of Ford vehicle hardware and software.
- Site Access Coordinator Manage access cards and database controlling the access to the Ford complex for 800+ employees in two separate buildings.
- Assist in the arrangements of floorplans and space planning management for a future site.
- Provide information to administrators and staff for the direction regarding activities, safety issues and/or proper maintenance of facilities and/or equipment.
- As the business continuity coordinator for Ford's Kanata Engineering Centre, I assist in the development, implementation and upkeep of the Business Continuity Planning Process Guide.

Emergency Management Officer

Public Services & Procurement Canada (PSPC), Real Property Branch - SPAR, NCA

September 2012 – March 2018

- Assisted in the development of Real Property Branch Business Continuity Management Plan (BCMP) and Crisis Management Plan (CMP)
- Provide proofreading and editing of branch plans, various exercises and guides
- Created & maintained a tracking system for the accountability of an inventory of Business Continuity Emergency Management notebook computers
- Delegate for two employees for the HRG travel system
- Designated as a GCDOCS super-user and information administrator acting as a point of contact for all GCDOCS issues and inquiries.
- Plan and schedule regular Business Continuity Planning (BCP) working group meetings

- Record minutes of BCP meetings to provide group with action items
- Collected data to update various guides and plans using Excel, Word, PowerPoint and Visio
- Maintained Human Resource files for a team of six.
- Procure, setup and update Business Continuity Emergency Management notebooks for distribution
- Performed duties of Unit Security Officer (USO) for security clearance inquiries and applications for the Strategic Planning Directorate of SPAR.

Executive Assistant to DG / Scheduling Assistant

PSPC, Real Property Branch – SPAR, NCA

June, 2015 – September 2015

- Coordinated the daily activities of the Director General
- Organized meetings and teleconferences, reserved boardrooms and processed travel arrangements
- Prepared correspondence
- Evaluated information requests from internal and external clients and ensured follow-up
- Processed and tracked ATIP requests and issues management files via CCM Mercury
- Provided administrative support (e.g. reviewing, responding and triaging of emails and other general administration requests).

Administrative/Lease Officer

PSPC, Real Property Branch - AFM, NCA

January, 2010 - September 2012

- Analyze capital expenditures for erroneous data compared to building conditioning reports
- Prepare/proofread reports, official letters and financial analysis for management.
- Implemented and oversee a records database concerning the sale and leaseback of seven government properties.
- General administrative duties/ research.
- Provide advice and guidance to regional employees concerning the Sale Lease Back initiative.

Business Support Officer/ Client Authority IT Asset Management (ITAM)

PSPC, Real Property Branch – Knowledge and Systems Management (KSM), NCA

February, 2008 - January 2010

- Supervised the day to day activities of the ITAM team/shop in absence of manager.

- Point of contact for procurement of all IT assets for Real Property Branch in the National Capital Region.
- Provided Client Authority support for Real Property Branch in the NCA.
- Lead administrator for the inventory tracking and data maintenance systems for IT crown assets.
- Principle communication point of contact for all RPB users for ITAM related inquiries.
- Created and processed Move Action Requests (MAR)
- Input & update IT asset and service management data using internal applications. (Service Request Management System SRMS, AssetFinder and CACTUS)
- Provide support for clients by implementing and communicating procedures.
- Monitored and responded to inquiries received via helpline and e-mailbox

Education

2018 - 2019

Cornell University - Ithaca, NY

- Business Data Analytics Certification

2010 - 2018

Canadian School of Public Service - Ottawa, ON

- OSSRO trained (Office Systems Service Request Online)
- SIGMA training (Administrative Officer Course)
- Real Property Management Fundamentals
- First Aid Training
- Unit Security Officer training course (USO)

Security Clearance

Secret

Languages

English – Fluent French – Intermediate

German – Basic

Italian - Basic